你竟然用手肘撞我的脸  小戴
I can't believe you elbowed me in the face, D.
那是意外  查尔斯  进来
It was an accident, Charles. Come inside.
我给你拿冰袋敷一下
I'll get you an ice pack.
薇琪  查尔斯来了
Vicky, I've got Charles with me.
薇琪
Vicky.
戴米安
Damian.
薇琪
Vicky.
我是说
I'm just saying,
两个人在一起过的第一个情人节
the first Valentine's Day you spend with somebody
是相当重要的
is important.
是  但蕾妮不在意那些  哥们
Yeah, but Lanie doesn't care about that stuff, bro.
是女人就都在意的  贝克特
All women care. Beckett,
你和乔什  你们都有节目了是吧
you and Josh-- you got big plans for Valentine's Day, right?
乔什是外科医生  而我是个警察
Josh is a surgeon. I'm a cop.
虽然周一晚上我俩都有空的可能性很小
In the unlikely event that we have a couple of hours free
但如果有空我们应该会共进晚餐
on Monday night, we might go to dinner.
看见了吧
See?
喂  卡塞尔  我是贝克特
Hey, Castle. It's Beckett.
听到留言请回电
Call me when you get this.
错过这件案子卡塞尔一定会失望的
Ooh, Castle's gonna be sorry that he missed this one.
-为什么  -关于有钱人的
- Why? - Rich people, man.
公众人物谋杀案总是最变态的
Society murders are always the freakiest.
大约一小时前报的案
The call came in about an hour ago.
房子的主人  戴米安·韦斯莱
The owner of the house, Damian Westlake...
说他下午五点离开去找邻居
says all was well when he left at 5:00 P.M.
查尔斯·厄特利打篮球时
to meet his neighbor, Charles Utley,
还一切正常
for a game of pickup.
当他们六点钟回来的时候
When the men returned at 6:00 P.M.
-维多利亚·韦斯莱就死了  -凶器呢
- Victoria Westlake was dead. - Murder weapon?
是钉枪  就在那儿
Nail gun. It's over there.
看  就跟你说很变态吧
See? Told you. Freaky.
后门半掩着
The back door was ajar.
有警员发现房子后墙上有疑似
Officers found what appears to be
帮派标志的图案
a gang tag on the rear wall of the building.
是刚漆上去的
The paint's fresh.
我去接触一下那个帮派
I'll reach out to the gang unit,
看看他们是否帮我们找出凶手
see if they can I.D. it for us.
我去找厄特利先生谈谈
And I'll talk with Mr. Utley.
韦斯莱家还有只狗
The Westlakes have a dog.
如果邻居听到狗叫声的话
So if neighbors heard barking,
我们就能确定案发时间了
we might be able to pinpoint a timeline.
我们已经询问过了  没人听见狗叫声
We've canvassed, and nobody heard the dog.
法医暂时确定死亡时间
The M.E. tentatively puts time of death
是在下午四点半到六点之间
between 4:30 and 6:00.
四点半  就是说她可能在她丈夫离开前
4:30,which means she might have been dead
就已经死了
before the husband left the house.
韦斯莱先生在哪儿  谢谢
Where is Mr. Westlake? Thank you.
韦斯莱先生  我是探长凯特
Mr. Westlake, I'm detective Kate...
卡塞尔
Castle.
卡塞尔  你怎么会在这儿
Castle, what are you doing here?
戴米安·韦斯莱是我从寄宿学校开始
Damian Westlake is an old friend of mine
就认识的一个老朋友
from boarding school.
他知道我和纽约市警察局的关系
He knows about my relationship with the NYPD.
他刚打电话给我向我寻求帮助
He just called me to give him some support.
当时你就该打电话
Which is when you should've
-通知我的  -我刚到
- called me to let me know. - I just got here,
而且我根本不知道这件案子由你负责
and I had no idea this would be your case.
那现在你知道了
Well, now that you do,
有什么和案情相关的内容
is there anything you want to tell me
要告诉我的吗
that might be pertinent?
没有  我甚至都没见过薇琪
Uh, nothing. I'd never even met Vicky.
但现在至少我能告诉戴米安
But now at least I can tell Damian
纽约市最好的探长正在调查
the finest detective in New York City
他妻子的案子
is working his wife's case.
她离开的时候还一切正常
Everything was fine when she left.
她和我说的最后一句话是"玩得开心点"
The last thing she said to me was, "Have a good game."
韦斯莱先生  你知道什么人可能会
Mr. Westlake, do you know of anyone
想要伤害薇琪吗
that might have wanted to harm Vicky?
不知道  大家都爱她
No, everyone loved her.
有人在你家后墙上喷了油漆
Someone spray painted your back wall.
你有注意到当你离开时
Did you notice anyone suspicious
附近有可疑人物出现吗
hanging out when you left?
没有  薇琪本来就不该这时候在家的
No. Vicky shouldn't even have been here.
因为头痛她提前下班了
She came home early from work with a headache.
我们会把凶手抓到的  放心吧
Hey. We're gonna catch the guy who did this, okay?
我保证
I promise.
她是做什么工作的
What did she do for a living?
室内设计
Interior design.
你呢
And you?
戴米安是个作家
Damian's a writer.
有我可能读过的作品吗
Anything I might have read?
没有  从来都没有发表过
No, I've never been published.
-你们结婚多久了  -五年
- How long were the two of you married? - Five years.
你会用幸福来形容你们的婚姻生活吗
And would you characterize your relationship as happy?
为什么你要问这个
Whoa. Why would you need to ask that?
没关系  里奇
It's all right, Ricky.
我很爱我妻子
I loved my wife very much.
她是我的全部
She was my whole world.
韦斯莱先生  很抱歉
Mr. Westlake, I'm sorry,
但我不得不问你一些
but I'm gonna have to ask you
有关凶器的问题
a few questions about the murder weapon.
为什么你要
Why would you need to
问他有关凶器的事
ask him about the murder weapon?
卡塞尔
Castle.
那把钉枪是你的吗
The nail gun, was that yours?
不是  我们在做装修
No. We've been doing some remodeling.
房子里的工具
Any tools in the house
-都是工匠们的  -你们有没有
- belong to the workmen. - Did you ever have any--
你们和工匠们有过争执吗
Were there ever any issues with these workmen?
是的  上周五晚上我无意中听到
Yeah, uh, I overheard Vicky on the phone
薇琪在电话里和什么人争吵
with someone last Friday evening.
她说他已经被解雇了
She told him he was fired
不该再到这儿来
and he shouldn't come back.
你知道他叫什么名字吗
You know his name?
不知道  我问过她  她说没什么
No, I asked her about it. She told me it was nothing.
去问安珀·帕丁丽吧  她是薇琪的员工
Talk to Amber Patinelli. Amber works for vicky.
如果你们不介意的话  我要打电话通知
Look, if--if you don't mind, I really need to call
薇琪的前夫西蒙 和她的孩子们
Vicky's ex-husband Simon and her kids.
我想媒体一定会大肆报道
I'm sure the press is gonna be all over this,
我不希望他们是从电视上得知这件事的
and I don't want 'em to hear about it on television.
-当然  -我离开一下
- Of course. - Excuse me.
你干嘛冲我发火啊
Hey. Why are you mad at me?
我只是看望朋友而已
I'm just looking out for my friend.
你在嫌犯面前挑战我的权威  卡塞尔
You challenged my authority in front of a suspect, Castle.
什么时候戴米安变成嫌犯了
Since when is Damian a suspect?
现在所有人都有嫌疑
Right now everyone is.
你知道的  这是我的工作方式
You know that. That's how I do my job.
我不会让你妨碍
I will not have you get in the way
-我查案  -不会  我不会  保证
- of an investigation. - I won't. I won't. I promise.
但现在我们能不能讨论一下
But now can we get on to
真正的嫌疑犯  比如工匠
real suspects, like workmen,
比如神秘的帮派成员
Like, uh, mystery gang members?
立刻展开审问
Question away.
听我说  我向戴米安保证过
Look, I promised Damian
我们会找出凶手
we would get the guy that did this.
让我帮你  拜托了
Let me help you. Please.
哎哟这不是卡塞尔么
Yo! Castle.
你赶上了
Hey, you made it.
我和戴米安·韦斯莱的朋友
Yeah. So I talked with
查尔斯·厄特利谈过了
Damian Westlake's friend, Charles Utley.
他说当戴米安看到妻子的尸体时
He said Damian was distraught
几乎失控
when he found his wife's body,
但他提到当他们像平常一样进行友谊赛时
but he also says that during their normally friendly game,
戴米安表现出不寻常的紧张和侵略性
Damian was unusually tense and aggressive.
所以有可能他先朝妻子射钉
So maybe he shoots his wife,
然后去打篮球
then goes to shoot some hoops,
弄伤他的朋友  带他进屋做不在场证明
injures his friend, brings him inside to establish an alibi.
薇琪·韦斯莱星期五和一个工匠
You know, Vicky Westlake had an argument
有过争执
with one of her workers on Friday.
这个工匠  就我目前所推测
A worker who, and I'm just speculating here,
是有经验使用钉枪的人
may have some experience with nail guns.
也许我们应该根据这条线索先查查清楚
Maybe we should go run and check out that lead
再对一个无辜的人做出草率的判断
before we rush to judgment on an innocent man.
打断下  这就是你说的不妨碍我工作吗
I'm sorry. Is this you staying out of the way?
我只是想说
This is me simply making a point
还有其他的目标嫌疑人
about remaining objective.
请问  你是安珀·帕丁丽吗
Excuse me. Amber Patinelli?
我是埃斯波西多警探  这位是莱恩警探
I'm detective Esposito. This is detective Ryan.
我们想和你谈谈薇琪·韦斯莱
We'd like to talk with you about Vicky Westlake.
当然  天哪  太可怕了
Of course. Oh, my god. It's just so terrible.
薇琪的丈夫说她曾经和
Vicky's husband said that she had a fight
她房子里的一个工匠起过争执
with one of the workmen at her house.
她开除了木匠  莫里斯·哈斯贝格
She fired the carpenter, Morris Hasberg.
天哪  你们不会以为莫里斯是凶手吧
Oh, my god. You don't think that Morris did this?
我们正在调查几个嫌疑人
We're looking at several suspects.
莫里斯干了什么会被开除
What did Morris do to get fired?
他偷了她的订婚戒指
He stole her engagement ring.
薇琪担心会被抢劫
Vicky was afraid of getting mugged,
所以她不常戴着  上周她在
so she didn't wear it much. Vicky looked for it
首饰盒里找戒指  结果发现不见了
in her jewelry box last week, and it was missing.
放在首饰盒里吗
Jewelry box?
我未婚妻从没把戒指从手上拿下来过
My fiance never takes her ring off her finger.
你未婚妻的戒指有11克拉吗
Is your fiance's ring 11 carats?
莫里斯受雇为主浴室做橱柜
Morris was hired to make a cabinet for the master bath.
卧室里只有他一个人
He was the only person in the bedroom.
薇琪说  如果他不把戒指交出来
Vicky told him, if he didn't return the ring,
她就要报警  莫里斯疯了
she'd have to call the police. Morris went crazy.
-怎么疯法  -星期一早上他来办公室
- Crazy how? - He came to the house on Monday morning,
大吵大闹
and he made a scene.
说如果她继续散播谣言
He said that if she didn't stop telling lies,
事情就不会好看了
bad things would happen.
莫里斯·哈斯贝格
Morris Hasberg?
看来韦斯莱家的木匠是在
Turns out the Westlakes' carpenter
纽约州新新监狱里学的手艺
learned his trade at Sing Sing,
九十年代末他因武装抢劫在那儿
where he did eight to ten for armed robbery
待了十来年
back in the late '90s.
有目击者称案发当天见到他的货车
Witnesses report seeing his truck in front of
停在韦斯莱家的别墅前
the Westlakes' town house on the day of the murder.
两位打的这么火热
Do I see two men jumping on
莫非是为了那个工匠嫌疑人么
a hot workmen-related lead?
呃  这话说出来怎么感觉这么腐
That sounded a lot dirtier than I--than I wanted it to.
-我们会把他带来的  -好的
- We'll bring him in. - Okay.
等下  那咖啡是买给...
Oh, actually, those were-- those...
看  我早说凶手不是戴米安了
See? I told you it wasn't Damian.
我从没说过他是
I never said it was.
事实上  如果莫里斯是
In fact, I would be very happy
我们要抓的人的话 我会很高兴的
if Morris was our guy.
你们抓错人了
You have wrong guy.
莫里斯  法医把钉枪送回来了
Morris, forensics came back on the nail gun.
报告显示上面都是你的指纹
Your fingerprints are all over the murder weapon.
我做木工时必须要用到钉枪
I must use the nail gun for carpenter.
那星期三你的货车为什么
Well, then what was your truck
会停在她家街上
doing parked on her street on Wednesday?
她让我去见她
She say come, uh, see her.
你以为我们会相信
You expect us to believe
在你偷了韦斯莱太太的戒指并威胁她之后
that Mrs. Westlake invited you back into her house
她还会请你回到她的别墅吗
after you stole her ring and threatened her?
韦斯莱太太  她找到了戒指
Mrs. Westlake, she found the ring.
她打电话给我让我过去
She called to me and say to come there,
然后她为指责了我向我道歉
and then she say sorry to accuse.
她哭了
She cry.
她哭了吗
She cry-- she cried?
是真的
Is true.
哈斯贝格的不在场证明
Hasberg's alibi
是真的
is truth.
-扯蛋呢吧  -犯罪现场单位清点过首饰
- Shut the front door. - C.S.U. inventoried the jewelry,
订婚戒指在里面
and the engagement ring is there.
但是凶器上还有别的指纹
But there were other prints on the weapon.
只是部分  都不在系统记录里
Partials, but none of them are in the system.
好吧  有什么新线索
Okay, so what's our new theory?
谁是我们新的嫌疑人
Who's our new suspect?
算了吧  不会是戴米安的
Oh, come on. Not Damian.
卡塞尔  当坏人
Castle, bad guys
带着武器闯进屋子时
breaking into houses bring their own weapons,
狗是会冲着陌生人叫的
dogs bark at strangers,
而且超过三分之一的
and over one-third
家庭女性凶杀案的受害者
of domestic female homicide victims
是被他们的丈夫所杀
are murdered by their husbands.
我不管什么数据
I don't care about statistics.
我告诉你  戴米安不会杀人
I am telling you, Damian is not capable of murder.
告诉你吧  我人生至今为止只遇到过三个人
You know, I could say that about maybe three people
让我敢担保他们不会杀人
that I've met in my entire life.
这个人有什么地方可以让你如此
What is it about this guy that--that warrants
坚定不移地担保他
this unshakable faith that you have in him?
我14岁时  妈妈送我去艾维克学院
When I was 14, my Mom sent me to Edgewyck Academy.
我想家  又没有朋友
I... I was homesick, and I didn't have any friends,
所以我就把一切都记录下来
so I wrote about it.
一天  我向文学杂志投稿
One day, I submitted a story to the literary magazine.
戴米安·韦斯莱是编辑
Damian Westlake was the editor.
他登了你的作品
And he published it.
不止是这样
More than that.
他把我叫到他的办公室
He called me down to his office,
他请我坐下  说"里奇"
he sat me down, and he said, "Ricky..."
"你很有天赋"
"You have a great talent."
以前从没人对我说过那样的话
No one had ever said anything like that to me before.
戴米安  他鼓励我  指导我  他
Damian, he encouraged me, he critiqued me, he...
他帮我挖掘出更深层的自我
he always made me dig a little deeper.
没有戴米安·韦斯莱  我可能会成为律师
Without Damian Westlake, I'm a lawyer,
骗子或者是放牧人竞技会上的小丑
I'm a grifter, I'm a rodeo clown,
总之我不会成为一个作家
but I am not a writer.
没有他  就没有现在的我
Without him, I'm not me.
我对戴米安·韦斯莱
Yo. I ran a standard background check
做了一个标准的背景调查
on Damian Westlake.
原来薇琪不是他第一个死于袭击的
Turns out Vicky isn't the first family member
-家人  -你是指他的父亲吗
- that he's lost to violence. - You mean his father.
戴米安19岁时  他父亲死在韦斯莱家
When Damian was 19, his father was killed
位于波多黎各的度假屋里
at the Westlake vacation home in Puerto Rico.
不是自然死亡  卡塞尔  而是谋杀
Not killed, Castle. Murdered.
你怎么没告诉我们这个
And you didn't tell us?
告诉你们什么
Tell you what?
二十年前戴米安的父亲是
H-how is the tragic death of Damian's father
怎么惨死的
over two decades ago
这和这件案子有什么关系吗
in any way relevant to this case?
我来告诉你有什么关系
I'll tell you how.
调查那件案子的警察
The cops that were investigating that case
将戴米安列为主要嫌疑犯
named Damian as the prime suspect.
翻译：摄氏零度   咖啡十三   小易   千花
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳   千花   后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
卡塞尔  讲朋友义气是一回事
Castle, it's one thing for you to look out for your friend.
但对我隐瞒重要线索
It's a completely different story
就完全是另外一回事了
when you hide vital information from me.
我没有想隐瞒  我只是觉得它不重要
I wasn't hiding it. I just didn't think it mattered.
你觉得戴米安曾是某起凶杀案的
You didn't think it mattered
主要嫌疑人这件事不重要
that Damian was a suspect in a previous homicide?
我不知道他是嫌疑人
I didn't know he was a suspect.
既然他从未被逮捕
And since he was never arrested,
而且那件案子一直没破
and that case is still unsolved,
我认为那些警察有很多假设
I'm guessing those cops have a lot of theories
但却没有证据证明  就像某位现在
and no evidence, like another detective I could name
站在我眼前的警官这样
right about now.
如果这是别人
You know, if this was anybody else,
你一定会在问我
you'd be asking me
为什么我还没有把他们铐起来
why I hadn't already slapped the cuffs on 'em.
但这不是别人
But it isn't anyone else.
而且我告诉你
And I'm telling you,
在这件案子上你错得离谱了
you are way off base on this one.
-怎么了  -老爸老妈吵架了
- What's going on? - Mom and dad are fighting.
谁占上风
Who's winning?
我们协商好了你在这件案子上
We agreed that you would stay out of my way
不能干涉我  -没错  但我没同意
on this. Yes, but I did not agree
我会袖手旁观让你们诬陷我的朋友
I would stand by and let you railroad my friend!
卡塞尔  这单案子你太感情用事了
Castle, you are too close to this one.
你必需回家
You need to go home!
现在就回
Now!
-没错  -谢谢你 比利
-Yeah...-Thanks, Billy.
非常感谢
Really appreciate that.
好  我会尽快  谢谢
Yeah, as soon as possible. Thank you.
好的
Okay.
我们看一下菲利普·韦斯莱案子的卷宗吧
Let's get ahold of Philip Westlake's case file.
我想查出为什么当时逮捕他
I want to find out why no arrests were made.
还有薇琪·韦斯莱的前夫西蒙·坎贝尔
And Vicky Westlake's ex-husband, Simon Campbell,
把他带到局里吧
let's bring him in.
不好意思  我必须出来透透气
Sorry. I... I had to get outta there.
我总感觉自己会听见薇琪说话
I keep thinking I'm gonna hear Vicky's voice
或者我走到拐角时
or I'm gonna come around the corner
看到她蜷缩着躺在沙发上
and see her curled up on the sofa.
听着 戴米安  我很抱歉
Listen, Damian, I'm sorry.
调查中出了一点事
Something's come up in the investigation.
你爸爸的谋杀案里  你是嫌疑人
Your father's murder...you were a suspect.
一些疯子闯进了我家
Some creep broke into our house,
洗劫一空  打死了我父亲
robbed the place, and shot my father.
警察从调查第一天起就认定我是凶手
The cops decided on day one that it must have been me.
你当时在那吗
Were you there?
我在两千英里外的大学里
I was at college, 2,000 miles away.
我知道你和你父亲的关系
I know you and your father didn't have
不是太好
the, uh, the best relationship.
我母亲去世后关系又恶化了
It only got worse after my mother passed away.
他死之后  你继承了
And when he died, you inherited...
所有财产
everything.
贝克特警官认为  我曾经逃脱了一次谋杀
Detective Beckett thinks, I got away with murder once,
现在我又重操旧业了  对吧
now I've done it again, doesn't she?
戴米安  你本应告诉我的
Ah, Damian, you should've told me.
我不是警察  我是你的朋友
I'm not a cop. I'm your friend.
没错  你是我的朋友
That's right. You are.
记得你第一次来艾维克的时候吗
Remember when you first came to edgewyck?
我记得
I remember.
是我告诉他们给你一个机会
I was the one that told them to give you a chance.
我现在也渴望一个这样的机会
I'm looking for the same chance now.
坎贝尔先生  你和你前妻关系如何
Mr. Campbell, how did you get along with your ex-wife?
有一阵子不大好  我那时很痛苦
Well, it was hard for a while. I was bitter.
薇琪为了他离我而去  你知道吗
Vicky left me for him, you know?
-嗯  -我们有家庭
- Mm-hmm.- We had a home.
我们有两个进入青春期的孩子
We had two kids going into their teens,
她却不可救药地爱上了戴米安·韦斯莱
and she fell madly in love with Damian Westlake
然后离我而去
and left me.
你了解他吗  关于他的过去
And what did you know about him, about his past?
我知道他没有工作  我猜他奔着钱来的
I know he doesn't work. Comes from money, I guess.
-嗯  -典型的从被宠坏的小孩
- Mm-hmm.- A typical spoiled child
成长为一个娇纵浪荡的男人
that grew into a spoiled man.
我知道薇琪后悔嫁给了他
I know Vicky regretted marrying him.
为什么你这么说
And why would you say that?
薇琪的店铺
Vicky's business
在我们房子的一楼
is on the ground floor of our brownstone.
我依然和孩子们住在上面的两层
I still live in the top two floors with the kids.
我每天都能见到她  听见她哼哼小曲
I would see her every day, you know, singing a little tune
爱不释手地看着他买给她的小玩意
or gazing fondly at some new bauble he had gotten her.
没过多久她不怎么唱歌了
Then lately, there was less
哭声却增多起来
singing and more crying.
周一时  她告诉我
Monday, she told me she
她觉得自己犯了个错误
thought she had made a mistake.
我们甚至谈到了复合
We even talked about getting back together.
难道你认为她两天后遇害
What, you think it's a coincidence
是个巧合吗
that two days later, she was dead?
理查德  我以为你早都睡觉了
Richard, I thought you went to bed hours ago.
我睡不着
Couldn't sleep.
睡不着是因为你和贝克特吵了一架
Couldn't sleep because of your fight with Beckett
还是因为你的老朋友戴米安
or because there's a possibility
有可能是两起凶杀案的凶手
Your old friend Damian may be a double murderer?
都有  感谢你这么直言不讳地说出来
Both, and thank you for putting it so bluntly.
理查德
Richard, you know...
别  别说出来
Don't. Don't say it.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking,
因为我也在想这个
'cause I'm thinking it, too.
戴米安的父亲和妻子都因
What are the chances Damian's father and wife
入室抢劫被害而他却与此毫无关系
are both murdered in home invasions,
这可能性能有多大
but he had nothing to do with 'em?
那你怎么认为
So what do you think?
我只知道  如果他是有罪的
I know, if he is guilty,
想说服我不仅仅需要一个合理的假设
I'll need to be convinced beyond a reasonable doubt.
我得看到实实在在的证据
I will need solid evidence,
不仅仅靠巧合和猜测
not just coincidence and speculation.
你难道见过贝克特
Have you ever known Beckett
仅仅满足于巧合和猜测么
to settle for less than that?
没有
No.
我觉得你需要面对事实  孩子
Then I think you should face it, kiddo.
你欠那个女人一声道歉
You may owe that woman an apology...
特别是如果你还想调查此案的话
especially if you want to stay on the case.
哦  不
oh, no.
我能帮你一把吗
Can I give you a hand with that?
我能搞定
I got it.
你只要... 把那个...
You just...all you do...
卡塞尔  我说过我能搞定  好吧
Castle, I said I got it. Okay?
你来这做什么
What are you doing here?
当我告诉戴米安
When I told Damian
纽约市最好的警官负责他妻子的案子时
the best detective in New York was working his wife's case,
我说的是真心话
I meant it, and I'm...
我很抱歉我曾经怀疑过你的能力
I'm sorry to have doubted you.
如果你让我回归  我保证
If you let me back, I promise,
我会尽全力保持一个客观的态度
I will do my best to remain objective.
这可能比你想象中要更难做到
Well, that might be harder than you think.
韦斯莱家的财务报告
The Westlakes' financial records.
这是他俩的婚前协定
This is their prenuptial agreement,
上面明确说如果他们离婚
and it's pretty clear that if they got divorced,
戴米安一个子儿也得不到  但如果她死了
Damian would get nothing, but with her dead,
-他会继承一千万美元  -没错
- he inherits $10 million.- Yes,
但你忘了戴米安已经很富有了
but you're forgetting that Damian is already rich...
他父亲死后继承的钱
the money he got when his father died.
是他父亲被谋杀后
When his father was murdered,
而且  那笔钱也已经花完了
and also, that money is gone.
戴米安用他的最后一笔现金来讨薇琪欢心了
Last of his cash, Damian spent wooing Vicky.
他用昂贵的礼物将她哄的团团转
He showered her with expensive presents...
订婚戒指  手链  钻石耳环
the engagement ring, a tennis bracelet, diamond earrings.
等到他们结婚的时候
And then by the time they got married,
戴米安的钱全都花光了
Damian was tapped out of money.
是薇琪付的所有账单
Vicky was paying for all the bills.
根据戴米安的信用卡收据
According to Damian's credit card receipts,
他用她的钱买上等苏格兰威士忌
he spent her money on good scotch,
剧院头等包厢和古巴雪茄
box seats, and cuban cigars.
于此同时  她绝大多数钱
Meanwhile, most of her charges are
花在她的设计事业上了
for her design business...
-一个叫鉴赏者的破地方  还有再塑者  -于是呢
-APPRAISER, a rug place, REFINISHER... - so?
也许薇琪厌倦了做他的提款机
So maybe Vicky got tired of being his A.T.M.
也许她威胁他
Maybe she threatened
她要像他父亲那样与他断交
to cut him off just like his father did.
卡塞尔  我看过
Castle, I read the
菲利普·韦斯莱案子的卷宗了
Philip Westlake case files.
警察可以确定就是他干的
The cops were sure it was him.
没错  但他们错了  就像你现在也错了
Yes, but they were wrong, just like you're wrong now.
抱歉  难道你这是在保持一个客观的态度吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Is this you being objective
还是在不干涉我的破案工作
or is this you staying out of my way?
我这是在说
This is me saying,
也许我们可以稍微扩大一下嫌疑犯的范围
maybe we could broaden our suspect pool a little bit.
肯定有一些其他我们需要调查的人
Certainly there's someone else we could be looking at.
我觉得我可以帮上忙
I think I might be able to help with that.
打黑小组查到了韦斯莱家
The gang unit I.D.'ed the tag
后墙上的符号
on the back wall of the Westlakes'.
是个人签名  那家伙的名字叫奥马·林肯
It's a personal signature. The guy's name is Omar Lincoln.
拜托了  告诉我他是个恶棍吧
Please, please tell me he's a very bad man.
他因2007年在一次入室抢劫中持械伤人
Well, he did two years for assault with a deadly weapon
而坐了两年牢
in a B&E in 2007.
已经给涂鸦治理小队打电话了
Called the graffiti squad.
他们已经在追踪他了
They've been tracking this guy.
查到了他的下落
Got a pop on his location.
太好了  我们去抓这个人吧
All right. Let's go get this guy, huh?
-好  去吧  我明白了  -谢谢
- Okay, go. I got it.- Thank you.
喂 奥马
Yo, Omar.
过来
Come here.
纽约警察局的  下来
NYPD, come on down.
好久不见  警官
So long, detective.
等一下
Hey, wait a minute!
纽约警察局的  快停车
NYPD! Stop the truck!
停车  停车  快停车
Stop! Stop the truck! Stop!
停车
stop the truck!
下来
Get down!
如果这是关于那个死去的富婆
Yo, if this is about that dead rich lady,
我可什么都不知道
I don't know nothin'.
好了  走吧  我们走吧
All right. Come on. Let's go.
好吧  我确实在房子里  但是我可没杀她
Okay, I was at the house, yeah. But I didn't kill her.
我觉得事情是这样的  奥马
Here's what I think happened, Omar.
你回到那面墙上涂鸦
You were back there tagging the wall.
韦斯莱夫人打开门看见了你
Mrs. Westlake opens the door and sees you.
你把她推到里面去
You shove her inside and
抓起你能找到的第一把武器
you grab the first weapon you find
这样她才不敢报警
so that she doesn't call the cops
而你也不会在保释期再次被抓
and you don't get busted on your parole.
不不  听着  我是在那扇墙上涂鸦了
No, no. Look, I tagged the wall.
那之后  我去六十三大街的花店了
Right after that, I hit the flower shop on 63rd.
店主看见我了
Owner sees me,
掏出了一把0.38口径的枪
pulls a .38,
我就赶紧走掉了
I get outta there hella fast.
-你们可以去问他  -那时几点
- You could ask him. - What time was this?
大约四点四十五
Quarter to 5:00, about.
你们只要不以破坏公物罪起诉我
You make this vandalism charge go away,
我就告诉你们这些勇猛的警探谁是凶手
I'll tell you fine detectives who did it.
好吧
Okay.
-她丈夫  -得了吧
- Her husband. - Ah, come on.
卡塞尔
Castle.
好吧  告诉我奥马
All right, Omar, talk to me.
我听见他们两个吵架了
I heard them two fighting.
整条公园大道都能听到那娘们的声音
I mean, beezy had her park avenue on.
"你是个大骗子  你是窃贼
"You're a liar. You're a thief.
我真后悔当初遇见你  我要离婚"
I'm sorry I ever met you. I want a divorce."
我要是他  我也会杀了她
If I was him, I woulda killed her, too,
就为了让她把嘴闭上
just to shut her up.
我的意思是...
I... I mean...
这句话别写上去
Don't write that.
我不敢相信你竟然相信了奥马·林肯的话
I can't believe you're taking Omar Lincoln at his word.
我是相信丹·萨缪尔斯的话
I'm taking the word of Dan Samuels,
他证实下午四点五十的时候  他在他的花店
who confirms, at 4:50 P.M., he was at his flower shop
拿一把0.38口径的枪指着奥马·林肯
pointing a .38 at Omar Lincoln,
之后奥马向北跑去
and that Omar ran north,
这正好是和韦斯莱家
which is in the opposite direction
相反的方向
of the westlakes' townhome.
没错  但他也许又折回来...
Yes, but maybe he doubled back...
奥马说他无意中听到韦斯莱一家
Omar says that he overheard the Westlakes
发生了激烈的争吵
having a knock-down-drag-out,
而且她提到了离婚
and that she used the "D" Word.
戴米安告诉我们他们俩没有矛盾
Damian told us that things were fine between them
薇琪对他说的最后一句话是
and that the last thing that Vicky said to him
"好好玩吧"
was "have a good game."
-他们吵架了  -两口子没有不吵架的
- They had a fight. - Married people fight.
那为什么戴米安要对我们撒谎
Well, then why did Damian lie to us about it?
也许他害怕你
Maybe he was afraid you'd, I don't know,
把他列为犯罪嫌疑人
suspect him of murder.
或许他害怕
Or maybe he was afraid
我们查出来吵架的原因
that we'd figure out what the fight was about.
这些是戴米安的信用卡消费记录
These are Damian's credit card charges.
没错  我们查过了
Yeah, we went over those.
雪茄威士忌剧院头等包厢什么的
Uh, cigars, scotch, box seats.
这是另外一张卡  费了点劲才找到
This is a different card. Took us a while to find it
因为戴米安是用他的
because Damian paid the
私房零花钱账户结的账
bill from a pocket account,
他将此事瞒着薇琪
and he kept it a secret from Vicky.
根据消费记录
And given the charges,
我很肯定他还隐瞒了其他事
I'm sure he's keeping other secrets.
有一个花店  还有购物中心里的几家珠宝店
There's a florist, some jewelry store at the mall,
他还在男性俱乐部租了一间娱乐室
and he rented a playroom at the varick club
-每周至少去一次  -娱乐室里面有什么
- at least once a week. - What's in a playroom?
顶多就是一张床什么的
Not much more than a bed.
没错  我也是俱乐部的会员
Yes, I'm a member.
那戴米安为什么在城里有一座好房子的
So why would Damian rent a bed
情况下还要租一张床呢
when he had a nice big town house?
肯定会有一个合乎情理的解释
There's gotta be a..a reasonable explanation.
那让我们看看能不能找到吧
Well, let's go see if we can find it.
卡塞尔先生  欢迎回来  好久不见
Mr. Castle, welcome back. It's been a long time.
没错  我最近有点忙于工作  没时间玩
Yes, well, I've been, uh, working a lot. No time for play.
我们这次来这其实
Ah. We're actually here about
是关于另一位会员的事
another one of your members.
戴米安·韦斯莱
Damian Westlake.
很显然他经常来这  租了一间娱乐室
Apparently he would come here often, rent a playroom.
我也许得给主管打个电话  我...
I should probably get my supervisor. I..
凯莉没关系  你可以告诉我们
Callie, it's okay. You can tell us.
戴米安在这和某人约会吗
Was Damian meeting someone here?
我们本不应该干涉会员的私事
We're not supposed to get involved with members,
尤其是已婚会员
especially married members.
但戴米安
But Damian...
我们情不自禁坠入情网
We couldn't help it. We fell in love.
他有说过要离开他妻子吗
Did he tell you that he planned on leaving his wife?
他有告诉你关于钱的问题吗
Did he tell you about the problems with the money?
没有  但韦斯莱夫人告诉我了
N-no. Uh, Mrs. Westlake did.
你跟韦斯莱夫人谈过了
You spoke to Mrs. Westlake?
她星期三上午过来的
She came to the club Wednesday morning.
说她已知道戴米安和我的私情
She said that she had figured it out, about Damian and me,
她想警告我
and she wanted to warn me.
警告什么
About what?
韦斯莱夫人说她要离开戴米安
Mrs.Westlake said that, she was going to leave Damian,
他一分钱也得不到
and then he wouldn't have any money.
她说他没有钱就活不了
She said he couldn't live without money,
因此他会再找一个
so he would find someone else.
可以养他的女人
You know, a woman who could support him.
你有告诉戴米安
And did you tell Damian
你和他妻子的谈话吗
about the conversation you had with his wife?
他对此说了什么
And what did he say?
他说他爱我
He said he loved me
什么也不能将我们分开
and that nothing would keep us apart.
接着我就在新闻上听到韦斯莱夫人出事了
Then I heard about Mrs. Westlake on the news.
在你听到戴米安妻子的谋杀案后
Did you talk to Damian
你有和他谈过吗
after you heard about his wife's murder?
只谈过一次
Just once.
他说我们近期不要见面了
He said we couldn't see each other for a while,
直到一切风平浪静后
until things calmed down.
他说不是他干的
He told me that he didn't do it.
但他又说  如果警察问起他
But then he said, you know, if the cops ask me,
我得说我们没有在一起
that I should say that we weren't together...
否则这对他很不利
That it could make him look bad.
我该怎么想呢
What am I supposed to think?
凯莉的不在场证据证实了
Callie's alibi checks out.
她周三一直工作到晚上7点
She was at work on Wednesday until 7:00 P.M.
警员正带戴米安过来
Uniforms are bringing Damian in now.
听着
Look...
也许戴米安是个白眼狼
Maybe Damian is a cheater
拆白党  黄世仁
and a bum and a bad husband.
-也许吗  -但这并不意味他是凶手
- Maybe?  - But that doesn't make him a killer.
你这样看着我
And you keep looking at me
好像我疯了才相信他
like I'm crazy for believing in him,
但这只是因为你不了解他
but that's just because you don't know him.
卡塞尔  你也不了解他
Castle, neither do you.
你自认为了解的戴米安并不存在
The Damian that you think you know doesn't exist.
他是你臆造的
You made him up,
就像你臆造的德里克·斯道姆
just like you made up Derrick Storm,
也像是你臆造的妮基·希特
just like you made up Nikki Heat.
他只不过是你14岁时思家心切
He's a character in a story that you told yourself
所创造出来的一个故事人物
when you were a homesick 14-year-old little boy.
也许是时候让他离开了
Maybe it's time to let him go.
你可以在观察室看
You can watch from observation.
你也不会想在场的
You don't want to be in there for this.
人们总跟我说该请个律师
You know, people keep telling me I should hire a lawyer.
我说我是清白的  我不需要律师
I say, I'm innocent. I-I shouldn't need a lawyer.
如果你是清白的  韦斯莱先生
If you're innocent, Mr. Westlake, why is it
为什么每一次我翻看这件案子
every time I turn over a rock in this case,
总能发现一些龌龊的秘密
some dirty secret of yours slithers out?
我没杀人
I didn't do this.
你在波多黎各也是这么跟警察说的
That's what you said to the cops in Puerto Rico, too.
总让自己深陷同样的窘境
Isn't funny how you keep finding yourself
说着同样的故事  不可笑吗
in the same situation, telling the same stories?
我也有个故事  想听听吗
I've got a story, too. You want to hear it?
一个英俊的小王子
My story is about a handsome little prince
只想过锦衣玉食的生活
who only ever wanted to live well,
所以他杀了自己的父亲  就是国王
so he killed his dad, the king,
偷了他所有的金子
and he stole all of his gold, and he spent it
花啊花  直至挥霍一空
and he spent it until it was all gone.
我不是为了钱才娶薇琪的
I didn't marry Vicky for her money.
我爱她
I loved her.
那凯莉呢
And what about Callie?
戴米安  我们跟她谈过了
Told you, Damian. We talked to her.
她说你爱的是她
She said that you were in love with her
你还告诉她
and that you told her
你想和她在一起
that you wanted the two of you to be together.
薇琪很快就会离开你的
Vicky was leaving you soon.
然后就可以自由享受你们的幸福了
You'd be free to have your happily ever after.
但有个问题
But there's just one problem.
再一次  你身无分文
Once again... You were out of gold.
薇琪阻碍了你的财路
Vicky stood between you and a fortune.
我们都清楚  人为了钱会不择手段
And we know what happens to people when they do that.
你是她生前最后一位见到的人
You were the last one to see her alive.
你是唯一有动机的人
You were the only one with motive.
但我没杀她
But I didn't kill her!
戴米安·韦斯莱
Damian Westlake,
你以谋杀维多利亚·韦斯莱
you are under arrest...
你搞错了
You're making a mistake.
的罪名被逮捕
for the murder of Victoria Westlake.
-你有权保持沉默  -我没杀人
- You have the right to remain silent.  - I didn't do this.
你有权请律师  如果你请不起
You have the right to an attorney. If you cannot...
阿丽克西斯起来走了
Alexis up and gone already?
是啊  她想在小提琴课之前
Oh, yeah. She wanted to
去商店展柜看看过个眼瘾
window shop before her violin lesson.
这是她和阿什利的第一个情人节
It's her first valentine's day with Ashley,
-她倍感压力  -是吗
- and she's feeling the pressure.  - Ah, yes.
她想要个礼物表明我爱你
She wants a gift that says "I love you,"
但没有什么可以表明
But nothing that says,
我爱你胜过一切
"I love you more than life itself.
请别离开我  否则我活不下去
Please don't leave me or I may die."
所以你们这些人
Well, that's why you guys go
就买巧克力和花
for the chocolates and the flowers.
我今天做的决定要是能这么简单就好了
I wish the choice I had to make today was so simple.
我意识到
I realized, I have the choice
我得在两件可怕的事情中选择一样
to believe in two terrible things.
要么相信戴米安是凶手
Either Damian is a killer
要么相信贝克特逮捕了一位无辜者
or Beckett's arrested an innocent man.
想想就头疼
Just thinking about it's making my head hurt.
那就不要想  倾听自己的心声
Well, then forget your head. Listen to your heart.
里奇
Ricky.
我一直回想起我高中时
I keep thinking back to when I was a senior.
你从哈佛辍学
You were off at Harvard.
你寄给我你写的小说
You'd send me pages you were working on for your novel,
写得很好  戴米安
and they were good, Damian.
你才华横溢  却为什么放弃了
Man, you had talent. Why'd you throw it away?
里奇  你才是作家  我不是
Ah, you were the writer, Ricky, not me.
我无话可说
I didn't have anything to say.
在我继承财产后
After I inherited all that money,
我甚至都不想再写了
I just didn't even want to try anymore.
但当我回顾过去的时候
But when I look back at my life,
希望你别介意
I hope you won't mind
我把你当成我的一项成就
if I list you as one of my few accomplishments.
你应该告诉我凯莉的事
You should've told me about Callie.
我向你发誓  我没杀我妻子
I swear to you, I didn't kill my wife.
好吧
All right.
你能想想我们还遗漏了什么
Can you think of anything we might have overlooked,
任何能证明你无罪的线索
anything that might speak to your innocence?
我起晚了  去了健身房
I slept in, I went to the gym,
在西区咖啡店吃了午餐
I had lunch in a cafe on the west side.
当我回到家  薇琪已经在家了
When I got home, Vicky was already there.
她见过凯莉了
She had been to see Callie.
我们吵了很久
We fought--god--for hours.
她说她要离婚
She said she wanted a divorce.
是的  她给我看了一个信封
Yeah, she--she showed me an envelope
说里面装着律师起草好
and said there were papers inside that her lawyer
等她签名的文件
had drawn up for her to sign.
她要结束这场婚姻
She was gonna end the marriage.
我乞求她重新考虑
I begged her to reconsider,
但她叫我离开
and she asked me to leave.
她需要想想
She needed to think.
你说薇琪给你一个信封
You said Vicky gave you an envelope?
长什么样
What'd it look like?
我还得回去工作
I gotta get back to my route.
只要5分钟  我保证
Just five minutes, I promise.
你好  你好
Ah. Hello, hello.
卡塞尔
Castle?
各位  这是布兰卡
Everyone, this is Blanca.
你好  您来这里有何贵干
Hola. Que estas haciendo aqui?
是这个疯小伙子把我拉来的
Este loco me hizo venir conmiel.
很抱歉  祝你好运
Ah. Lo siento. Buena suerte.
没错  我不懂你说什么
Yeah, I don't-- I don't know what...
首先
So first of all,
你是对的
You were right.
薇琪死的当晚  戴米安的确和她吵过架
Damian and Vicky did have a fight the night she died.
她的确说过要离婚
And she did tell him she wanted a divorce.
事实上
As a matter of fact,
她亮出一个大信封  装满了
She showed him a large manila envelope full of papers
她即将签字的法律文件
from her lawyer that she was going to sign.
装有法律文件的信封
An envelope with legal papers?
鉴证组的报告没提这事
There wasn't anything about this in the C.S.U. Report.
没错
Exactly.
布兰卡  请告诉他们发生了什么事
Blanca, please tell them what happened to it.
然后我就可以回去了
Then I could go back to my route?
当然
Yes, of course.
我星期三下午正在送信
I was delivering the mail on Wednesday afternoon.
当我沿着69街往公园方向走时
As I made my way up 69th towards park, I passed
遇到韦斯莱和厄特利先生  打了招呼
Mr. Westlake and Mr. Utley. I said hello.
他们也向我问好  几分钟后
They said hello back. A couple of minutes later,
我来到韦斯莱家  门开了
I get to the Westlakes' residence, the door opens,
韦斯莱夫人跑出来
Mrs. Westlake comes running out
给我一个大信封
and hands me a large manila envelope.
她说要确保
She said she wanted to make sure
和当天的信件一起寄出去
it went out in that day's mail.
等等  你确信
Wait a minute. So you're positive
你见到戴米安后见到韦斯莱夫人
that you saw Mrs. Westlake after you saw Damian?
女士  我再确信不过了
Lady, I couldn't be more sure.
-还有其他吗  -就这些  谢谢
- Anything else?  - No, that's it. Thank you.
-那我走了  -当然可以
- Then I'm leaving now.  - Of course.
谢谢你  布兰卡
Thank you, Blanca.
戴米安走后  薇琪还是活着的
So... Vicky was alive after Damian left the house.
他一直和查尔斯·厄特利在一起
and he was with Charles Utley
直到他们回来发现她死了
until they came back and found her dead.
也就是说
Which means...
戴米安不可能杀她
Damian couldn't have killed her.
收到
Got it.
检察官刚把戴米安·韦斯莱放了
The D.A.'s office just kicked Damian Westlake loose.
他们对此也不是太乐意
And they weren't too happy about it either.
长官  如果不是韦斯莱杀的
Sir, if Westlake didn't do it,
那就是他雇凶杀人
then he hired someone else to do it for him,
-一如他之前的手法  -你不是说
- Just like he did the last time.  - Wasn't it you that said
坏人总是亲自动手吗
that bad guys always bring their own weapons?
当他们想伪装成
Not when they want it to look
入室抢劫时就不是这样
like a push-in robbery gone wrong.
那狗没叫又怎么解释
What about the dog that didn't bark?
他让狗熟悉这个人
He got the dog used to the guy.
得了吧  你就是抓住
Come on. You just can't get over the fact
戴米安是他父亲谋杀案
That Damian was a person of
的嫌疑人不放
interest in his father's murder.
我不能忽视这里有个作案模式
I won't ignore the fact that there is a pattern here.
和这家伙亲近的人死的很惨
People close to this guy seem to die violently.
也许是有人利用戴米安悲惨的过去
Or maybe someone is using Damian's tragic past
陷害他杀了薇琪
to frame him for Vicky's murder.
现在有另一个嫌疑人摆在你面前
Now there's another suspect right in front of you
你连看都不看  他有动机
that you're not even looking at--someone who had motive,
手法和时机
Means, and opportunity.
那人到底是谁呢
And that would be whom exactly?
西蒙·坎贝尔
Simon Campbell
薇琪的前夫
Vicky's ex-husband.
想想看
Think about it.
被甩又被戴绿帽子的西蒙
Abandoned, cuckolded Simon--
我们了解他吗
do we really know this guy?
我们了解他的能力吗
Do we have any idea what he's capable of?
我们了解吗
Well, do we?
所有的证据都指向戴米安
All the evidence points to Damian.
是的  但如果戴米安没有旧谋杀案缠身
Yes, but wouldn't that evidence be less conclusive
证据还会像
if Damian didn't have this
现在这么确凿吗
old murder hanging over his head,
或者更好是  若有证据显示菲利普·韦斯莱
or better yet, if there was proof that Philip Westlake
是被入室窃贼杀死的呢
Was killed by a random intruder?
卡塞尔  没有证据
Castle, there isn't any proof.
还没有证据
Not yet, there isn't.
既然你不能拨开围绕戴米安的疑云
Since you can't see through the cloud of suspicion
那我来拨开云雾见青天吧
surrounding Damian, I'm gonna clear the air.
我要破掉菲利普·韦斯莱的谋杀案
I'm gonna solve Philip Westlake's murder,
证明我的朋友没杀人
prove my friend didn't do it.
与此同时  你可以查查西蒙·坎贝尔
Meanwhile, you can check out Simon Campbell.
我需要确凿证据去找检察官
I need to go to the D.A. with something solid.
你能证明韦斯莱雇凶杀死他妻子吗
Can you prove Westlake hired somebody to off his wife?
我需要一些时间
I just need a couple of days.
那我们下一步该怎么办
So what's our next move?
如果戴米安雇凶杀死薇琪
If Damian hired someone to kill Vicky,
肯定会有钱财线索
then there's a money trail.
我去找找
I'll find it.
与此同时  你们去查查西蒙·坎贝尔
Meanwhile, you guys look into Simon Campbell.
我肯定他会喜欢的
I'm sure he'll love it.
-亲爱的  你女儿真是天才  -我早知道了
- Darling, your daughter's a genius.  - I knew that already.
情人节  她给阿什利买了个相框
For valentine's day, she bought Ashley a frame,
上面刻着真爱
had it engraved "True love,"
放上他宠物鼠西奥多的照片
and put in a picture of his pet rat--Theodore.
诚挚又幽默  天才
Heartfelt yet humorous. Genius.
箱子里是什么
What's in the box?
菲利普·韦斯莱谋杀案的档案
This is Philip Westlake's murder file.
我告诉贝克特  我要破掉这案子
I told Beckett, I'm gonna solve the case.
理查德
Oh, Richard.
干嘛啊
What? You're the one
不是你告诉我要听从心声么
who told me to follow my heart.
话是这么说  但是...
Yes, but, you know--
但爸爸  这案子年龄比我还大
Dad, that case is older than me.
你们懂不懂爱与支持啊
This doesn't sound like encouragement.
那你要我帮忙吗
Then would you like some help?
当然要
Yes, I would.
雇凶杀人  需要钱
To hire a gunman, you need cash,
但是依据我们手头上
and according to everything
已经掌握的证据
that we've been through here,
-戴米安身无分文  -没错
- Damian didn't have any.  - Yeah, well,
可能在某处  我们没找到而已
it's somewhere. We just haven't found it yet.
房子里的奢华摆件
All the expensive knickknacks in that house,
也许他典当了一件小雕像
maybe he pawned a figurine.
薇琪是位设计师  一丝不苟
Vicky was a designer. She was meticulous.
如果有东西不见了  她肯定会留意到
She would've noticed if something went missing,
就比如订婚戒指
like the engagement ring.
想到什么了
Got something?
奥马·林肯听到薇琪说戴米安是个贼
Omar Lincoln overheard Vicky call Damian a thief,
当薇琪向莫里斯·哈斯贝格道歉
and when Vicky apologized to Morris Hasberg
指控他偷了订婚戒指时
for accusing him of stealing her engagement ring,
她哭了
she cried.
也许她并不是因为莫里斯才哭的
Maybe she wasn't crying because of Morris.
也许是因为她
Maybe she was crying because
突然意识到她的丈夫
she realized that her husband
才是小偷
was stealing from her.
鉴证组说正是那枚戒指
C.S.U. said the ring was accounted for.
薇琪的信用卡  不是有一位估价官吗
Vicky's credit card--wasn't there an appraiser on it?
是的  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
我知道戴米安金钱的来路了
I think I know how Damian got his money.
太可怕了  韦斯莱女士怎么了
It was terrible, what happened to Mrs. Westlake.
她周二下午来找你了
She came to see you Tuesday afternoon.
为了什么事
What for?
噢  她想做珠宝鉴定
Oh, she wanted her jewelry appraised.
我恐怕鉴定的结果是坏消息
I'm afraid I had some bad news for her.
钻石是仿冒的  我常看到
The stones were imitation. I see that quite a bit.
有的人急需要钱
People need cash in a hurry,
但又不想卖掉珠宝
but they don't want to give up their jewelry.
于是他们卖掉上面的钻石
So they sell the diamonds and they replace them
用高质量碳化硅代替
with high-quality silicon carbide.
其中是否有十一克拉的订婚戒指
Was one of the pieces an 11-carat engagement ring?
没错  整个底座都被更换了
Yes, the entire basket setting had been replaced.
她说就是这样她才发觉不对劲
She said that's how she knew something was wrong.
整个案子文档
This whole case file
又将嫌疑引回戴米安身上
is just one long loop leading back to Damian.
显然  邻居看到案发当晚
Apparently, neighbors saw someone loitering
有人在韦斯莱家附近徘徊
outside the Westlake home the night of the murder.
这是嫌犯的画像
Here's a sketch.
怎么了
What?
阿丽克西斯  我认识这家伙
Alexis, I know this guy.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
我们能谈谈吗
Could we talk for a moment?
当然
Sure.
你是来道歉的吗
Have you come to apologize?
不
No.
至少你很诚实
At least you're honest.
有什么需要帮忙的  探长
What can I do for you, detective?
你能让我看看你从
You could show me the diamonds
薇琪那儿偷来的钻石吗
that you stole from Vicky.
我找过华莱士·本纳了
I spoke to Wallace Benner,
西边的珠宝商
the jeweler on the west side.
他说他将你妻子
He said that he replaced
的钻石换成了仿冒品
your wife's diamonds with imitation ones.
几周换一次
Over a period of several weeks,
他替换了二十六颗钻石
He exchanged 26 diamonds
共价值八百万
worth over $8 million
真品全在你手上
and gave you the real ones.
这不是和你的猜测自相矛盾吗
But doesn't this argue against your theory
说是我杀了她
that I killed my wife?
要是我有八百万  为什么不跟凯莉
If I have $8 million, why wouldn't I just leave,
-远走高飞  -贪婪
- be with Callie? - Greed.
你利用第一颗钻石做定金
You used the first diamond as a down payment
雇了人杀她
for the contract to kill her.
只要薇琪死了
Once Vicky was dead,
你就能继承遗产得到双倍的钱
you'd inherit and double your take.
你真的认为我有这么冷血吗
You really think I'm that cold?
我个人是这么认为
Personally, I have no doubt.
但理查德·卡塞尔相信你
But Richard Castle believes in you,
而我信任他
and I believe in him.
让我看看那些钻石
So show me those diamonds.
让我看看它们是否齐全
Show me that none of them are missing
否则我就再把你关进大牢
or I will haul your ass back to jail.
我只替换了我送给她的钻石
I only changed the diamonds I had given her.
那些珠宝花了我几百万
Those pieces cost me millions of dollars,
而我知道一旦我们离婚
and I knew she'd have no
这些珠宝对她
particular attachment to them
不再有意义
once we were over.
我这一辈子
I've led....
都过着挥金如土  放浪形骸的日子  探长
a careless and wasteful life, detective.
但我不是个杀手
But I'm no killer.
二十六颗钻石  全都在这
26 diamonds-- they're all there.
萨拉查探长
Detective Salazar?
我是理查德·卡塞尔
I'm Richard Castle.
很感谢你抽空来见我
Thank you very much for meeting me.
我已经退休了  你可以叫我雷
I'm retired now, so you can call me Ray.
好的  那么雷  什么样的男人
All right. So, Ray, what kind of man
会离开美丽的波多黎各
leaves beautiful Puerto Rico
来到严寒的纽约过退休生活
to retire in freezing cold new york?
那男人娶了来自长岛的
The kind of man whose beautiful wife
漂亮老婆
is from long island.
-明白了  -那么你在电话里说
- Understood. - So you said on the phone
-这是关于菲利普·韦斯莱的案子  -没错
- this was about the Philip Westlake case? - That's right.
我真的很讨厌在退休时留下未破的案子
I really hated leaving the job with that one still unsolved.
或许我能帮上忙
Well, maybe I can help with that.
你知道案发当晚  邻居在
Did you ever manage to identify the man
韦斯莱家外看到的那名男子
that neighbors saw outside the Westlake home
-是谁吗  -我们应该查到了
- the night of the murder? - Thought we did.
那很像是当地的恶棍
He looked a lot like a local tough
叫做恩里克·莫利纳
named Enrique Molina.
但当我逮捕莫利纳后
But when we brought Molina in,
邻居没法指认他
the neighbors couldn't pick him out of a lineup.
因为那不是莫利纳
That's because it wasn't Molina.
-继续说  -迈克尔·鲁瑟福
- I'm listening. - Michael Rutherford
在艾维克学院得到了奖学金
was a scholarship kid at edgewyck academy,
他是戴米安·韦斯莱和我的校友
where Damian Westlake and I went to school.
他很聪明  但有反社会人格
He was smart, but... A sociopath,
他是个小偷
a thief.
很艰难才毕业
Kid barely graduated.
卢瑟福和韦斯莱是朋友吗
Were Rutherford and Westlake friends?
不  事实上  就是戴米安向校长
No. As a matter of fact, it was Damian who turned him in
告发他行窃的
to the headmaster for stealing.
但他们有相同的社交圈子
But they did run in some of the same circles,
偶尔会在派对上遇见
sometimes went to the same parties.
要是迈克尔·鲁瑟福听说了
What if Michael Rutherford heard
韦斯莱在波多黎各的度假屋
about the Westlake vacation home in Puerto Rico?
几乎长年空置  里面尽是财宝
It was nearly always vacant, full of treasure.
他可以小赚一笔
He could've made a small fortune
同时向戴米安复仇
and gotten revenge on Damian at the same time.
嘿  进展如何
Hey, how'd it go?
戴米安·韦斯莱是个小偷和骗子
Damian Westlake is a thief and a cheater...
但他或许不是我们要找的杀手
but he might not be our killer.
伙计们  我不想承认
You guys, I hate admitting it,
但卡塞尔或许是对的
but Castle might be right.
我们也觉得卡塞尔是对的
We've also been thinking that Castle might be right.
关于西蒙·坎贝尔资料
Info's back on Simon Campbell.
薇琪的前夫就是
Vicky's ex-husband is
人们所说的百万"负"翁
what they like to call "Overextended."
坎贝尔的房地产公司两年前遭受打击
Campbell's real estate firm took a big hit two years ago,
他为了挽回损失债台高筑
and he borrowed heavily to cover costs.
这家伙急需现金
The man needs a cash transfusion, stat.
西蒙 在薇琪的遗嘱上吗
Is Simon in Vicky's will?
他得到了房子的契约
He gets the deed to the brownstone,
价值五百万以上
which is worth over $5 million.
他还是孩子们财产的执行人
He's also the executor of their children's estate.
案发当时
Now he was at home
他跟三个孩子在家
with the kids at the time of the murder,
但他在二楼  而他们在三楼
but he was on the second floor, and they were on the third.
他大可以偷偷出去
So he could've snuck out,
在没人发现前再溜回来
been back before anyone noticed.
线索领我们到了坎贝尔的房子
Which brings us to the Campbell Brownstone
这个保安系统非常复杂
and its very sophisticated security system.
每道门  每扇窗户都有记录
It records every door opening, every window.
一个和蔼的检察官给了我们搜查令
A friendly A.D.A. Got us a warrant,
我们跟警报公司谈过了
and we talked to the alarm company.
星期三下午四点三十七分  前门打开了
4:37 p.M. On Wednesday, the front door opens.
在五点四十二分又开了一次
5:42, it opened again.
就是说  有人在案发前出去了
Which means someone left before the murder
之后回来了
and then returned after.
我想跟西蒙·坎贝尔先生谈谈
You know, I'd like to talk to our Mr. Simon Campbell.
我们打去他家
Well, we called his place.
他整晚都出去处理私人事务
He's out all evening on personal business
而且电话也不接
and he's not picking up his cell phone.
好的  去他家等他
Okay, sit on his house.
他一回家就带他过来
When he gets back home, bring him in. Mm.
那么  你打算情人节要怎么
So... What did you decide about Lanie
跟蕾妮渡过
and valentine's day?
噢  保险一点  带上礼物约她出来
Oh. I'm gonna play it safe and show up with a gift.
我找到家珠宝店  你知道的
I found this jewelry store that sells stuff, you know,
女孩子都喜欢项链  手镯
that girlfriends like-- necklaces, charm bracelets.
那么你呢  你打算准备什么
What about you? What are you gonna do?
噢  珍妮喜欢巧克力
Oh, Jenny loves chocolate.
珍妮在筹备婚礼
Jenny's planning her wedding.
你女友在节食
Your girl's on a diet,
而你打算送她巧克力吗
and you're gonna give her chocolate?
嘿  嘿  嘿  那是西蒙
Hey, hey, hey. It's Simon.
噢  看来他有自己的小情人啊
Oh, and he's got a little valentine of his own,
是不
doesn't he?
那是安珀·帕丁丽吗
Is that Amber Patinelli,
薇琪·韦斯莱的雇员
Vicky Westlake's employee?
你确定是她吗
You're sure it's her?
亏西蒙 还有脸说
So much for Simon saying
他想和薇琪复合
that he wanted to reconcile with Vicky.
你要我们怎么做
What do you want us to do?
我想也是
Thought so.
把他们俩带进来
Let's bring 'em both in.
我还希望你没走
I was hoping you'd still be here.
我刚打算打给你
I was just about to call you.
我想我知道谁是凶手了
I think I know who the killer is.
-我很感谢你能来  -已经很晚了  探长
- I appreciate you coming in. - Detective, it's very late.
噢  不会耽误你太久  我没发觉
Oh, this will be quick. I didn't realize
你们俩是情侣
that the two of you were a couple.
并不是正式的
Well, it's very casual.
我们是老朋友了
Well, for a long time, we were just friends.
我是他离婚时的精神支柱
I was a shoulder to cry on after the divorce.
直到最近我们才  呃
It's been only been recently that, uh...
-情人节有什么计划  -没啥特别的
- Any plans for valentine's day? - Uh, nothing special, no.
你希望和薇琪一起过  对吧
You were hoping to spend it with Vicky, right?
什么意思
What does that mean?
西蒙
Simon?
薇琪和我交谈过  仅此而已
Uh, Vicky and I have been talking. That's all.
这有什么关联吗  探长
How is this relevant to anything, detective?
薇琪知道你和安珀在一起吗
Did Vicky know about you and Amber?
不  我不想让她知道
No. I didn't want her to know.
那么有可能薇琪向安珀倾诉
So it's possible that Vicky innocently confided
告诉她  自己要离开戴米安
in her friend Amber, telling her she was leaving Damian,
回到西蒙 身边
going back to Simon,
但并不知道你们有一腿
not knowing that he was your Simon now.
安珀你在星期三下午四点十五分
Amber, you called for a company car at 4:15
叫了计程车
On Wednesday afternoon.
我跟刚跟调度员谈过了
We just talked to the dispatcher.
他说你雇了一个小时的轿车
He says you ordered a sedan and kept it for an hour,
往返韦斯莱家
a round-trip to the Westlakes' and back.
我们在钉枪上
We found a nail gun
找到了无法辨认的指纹
with fingerprints that we couldn't identify.
如果跟你的对比一下
If we compare them to yours,
你说会吻合吗
do you think we'd find a match?
你不是要去杀她的  是吧
You didn't go there intending to kill her, did you?
不
No.
我只是想聊聊
I just wanted to talk.
她可以找任何男人
She could have any man she wanted.
我求她把你让给我
And I begged her to let me have you.
她说不
She said no.
我太爱你了
I love you so much.
她永远不可能像我那样爱你
She could never love you the way that I do.
那么你是说
So you're saying that
安珀根本不知道我的过去
Amber didn't even know about my past?
并不是要陷害我  只是个怪异的巧合
It wasn't a frame, just a strange coincidence?
或是天意
Or kismet.
你要去哪里
Where are you off to?
巴塞罗纳
Barcelona.
我得离开这里
I gotta get away.
代我谢谢贝克特探长  好吗
Thank detective Beckett for me, will ya?
恭喜她破案了
Congratulate her on solving the case.
老实说  我们破了两件案子
Well, actually, we solved two cases.
这是什么
What's this?
那是迈克尔·鲁瑟福的画像
That's a sketch of Michael Rutherford.
我在你父亲的档案里找到的
I found it in your father's murder file.
迈克尔·鲁瑟福
Michael Rutherford?
学校里的
From school?
我不明白
I don't understand.
他闯进了你的家  杀了你父亲
He broke into your house. He shot your father.
噢  我的天
Oh, my god.
我们已经逮捕他了
They found him, Damian. He's been arrested.
这么长时间后
After all this time?
还能证明他有罪吗
Can they even prove that he did it?
凶案现场有一根烟蒂
There was a cigarette butt left at the scene.
萨拉查探长确保那有好好保存
Detective Salazar made sure it was preserved.
DNA吻合
The D.N.A s a match.
迈克尔做了笔交易  戴米安
Michael made a deal, Damian.
他认罪了
He confessed.
这真是
Wow. This is, uh...
太令人惊讶了
It's pretty overwhelming.
我还要赶飞机
I got a plane to catch,
或许我们晚点再聊
so maybe we should just talk about this later.
迈克尔认罪说你去找他
Michael told the cops you got in touch with him,
问他想不想
asked him if he wanted to make
在一晚上狠赚一笔
a lot of money for one night's work.
你把劳力士手表跟车子付作定金
You gave him your rolex and your car as a down payment.
当你继承财产后
When your inheritance came through,
他得到了五十万美元
he got half a million dollars
还有去洛杉矶的单程机票
And a one-way ticket to los angeles.
他还保存着那只劳力士表
He still has your rolex...
还有你画给他的地图
And a map that you drew
画了你父亲的房子
of your father's house
清楚画着到他的卧室的路线
with a path leading straight to his bedroom.
里克  他在撒谎  他在撒谎
Rick, he's lying. He's lying.
告诉我你没有这样做
Tell me you didn't do it.
里奇  我
Ricky, I...
告诉我这些时间我没有白白
Tell me I haven't been believing in you all this time
信任你
for nothing.
他们来了
That's them--
萨拉查探长和一些纽约警官
Detective Salazar and some New York detectives.
他们是来逮捕你的
They're here to take you in.
我跟他们说了你会配合的
I told them you'd be a gentleman.
给我一位英雄  我还你一出悲剧
Show me a hero, and I'll write you a tragedy.
艾夫·斯科特·菲兹杰拉德说的
F. Scott Fitzgerald said that.
那这个肯定是欧内斯特·海明威说的了
Then it must have been Ernest Hemingway who said,
伙计  我现在得去喝一杯了
"Man, I sure could use a drink right about now."
一起去吧  我请
Lead the way. I'm buying.
这是情人节
It's valentine's day.
你不是应该在一家烛光摇曳的餐厅
Shouldn't you be in a nice candlelit restaurant
穿着新裙子点餐吗
wearing a new dress ordering surf and turf?
我还有几小时空档
I've got a couple of hours.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事  我很好
Yeah. I'm fine.
大骗子
Liar.